[
    {
        "answer": "work",
        "question": "His __________ is also known for its influence on the philosophy of science.",
        "similar_words": [
            "acting",
            "aid",
            "attempt",
            "behavior",
            "behavior",
            "burst",
            "buzz",
            "calibration"
        ],
        "title": "Albert Einstein",
        "url": "https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Albert_Einstein"
    },
    {
        "answer": "general public",
        "question": "He is best known to the __________ __________ for his mass\u2013energy equivalence formula E = mc2, which has been dubbed \"the world's most famous equation\".",
        "similar_words": [],
        "title": "Albert Einstein",
        "url": "https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Albert_Einstein"
    },
    {
        "answer": "discovery",
        "question": "He received the 1921 Nobel Prize in Physics \"for his services to theoretical physics, and especially for his __________ of the law of the photoelectric effect\", a pivotal step in the development of quantum theory.",
        "similar_words": [
            "acquiring",
            "action",
            "activity",
            "assumption",
            "causing",
            "communication",
            "delivery",
            "departure"
        ],
        "title": "Albert Einstein",
        "url": "https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Albert_Einstein"
    },
    {
        "answer": "son",
        "question": "The __________ of a salesman who later operated an electrochemical factory, Einstein was born in the German Empire, but moved to Switzerland in 1895, forsaking his German citizenship the following year.",
        "similar_words": [],
        "title": "Albert Einstein",
        "url": "https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Albert_Einstein"
    },
    {
        "answer": "teaching diploma",
        "question": "Specializing in physics and mathematics, he received his academic __________ __________ from the Swiss Federal Polytechnic School in Z\u00fcrich in 1900.",
        "similar_words": [],
        "title": "Albert Einstein",
        "url": "https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Albert_Einstein"
    },
    {
        "answer": "year",
        "question": "The following __________, he acquired Swiss citizenship, which he kept for his entire life.",
        "similar_words": [
            "air alert",
            "bimester",
            "bimillennium",
            "bout",
            "bronze age",
            "calendar day",
            "calendar month",
            "century"
        ],
        "title": "Albert Einstein",
        "url": "https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Albert_Einstein"
    },
    {
        "answer": "work",
        "question": "After initially struggling to find __________, from 1902 to 1909 he was employed as a patent examiner at the Swiss Patent Office in Bern.",
        "similar_words": [
            "acting",
            "aid",
            "attempt",
            "behavior",
            "behavior",
            "burst",
            "buzz",
            "calibration"
        ],
        "title": "Albert Einstein",
        "url": "https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Albert_Einstein"
    },
    {
        "answer": "beginning",
        "question": "Near the __________ of his career, Einstein thought that the laws of classical mechanics could no longer be reconciled with those of the electromagnetic field.",
        "similar_words": [
            "accident",
            "accompaniment",
            "appearance",
            "avalanche",
            "boom",
            "case",
            "change",
            "collapse"
        ],
        "title": "Albert Einstein",
        "url": "https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Albert_Einstein"
    },
    {
        "answer": "special theory",
        "question": "This led him to develop his __________ __________ of relativity during his time as a patent clerk.",
        "similar_words": [],
        "title": "Albert Einstein",
        "url": "https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Albert_Einstein"
    },
    {
        "answer": "annus mirabilis",
        "question": "In 1905, called his __________ __________ ('miracle year'), he published four groundbreaking papers which attracted the attention of the academic world; the first paper outlined the theory of the photoelectric effect, the second explained Brownian motion, the third introduced special relativity, and the fourth mass\u2013energy equivalence.",
        "similar_words": [],
        "title": "Albert Einstein",
        "url": "https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Albert_Einstein"
    },
    {
        "answer": "year",
        "question": "That __________, at the age of 26, he was awarded a PhD by the University of Zurich.",
        "similar_words": [
            "air alert",
            "bimester",
            "bimillennium",
            "bout",
            "bronze age",
            "calendar day",
            "calendar month",
            "century"
        ],
        "title": "Albert Einstein",
        "url": "https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Albert_Einstein"
    },
    {
        "answer": "skepticism",
        "question": "Although initially treated with __________ from many in the scientific community, Einstein's works gradually came to be recognised as significant advancements.",
        "similar_words": [
            "incredulity",
            "indecision",
            "mental reservation",
            "misgiving",
            "peradventure",
            "suspense"
        ],
        "title": "Albert Einstein",
        "url": "https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Albert_Einstein"
    },
    {
        "answer": "year",
        "question": "He was invited to teach theoretical physics at the University of Bern in 1908 and the following __________ moved to the University of Zurich, then in 1911 to Charles University in Prague before returning to ETH (the newly renamed Federal Polytechnic School) in Z\u00fcrich in 1912.",
        "similar_words": [
            "air alert",
            "bimester",
            "bimillennium",
            "bout",
            "bronze age",
            "calendar day",
            "calendar month",
            "century"
        ],
        "title": "Albert Einstein",
        "url": "https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Albert_Einstein"
    },
    {
        "answer": "quantum theory",
        "question": "He continued to deal with problems of statistical mechanics and __________ __________, which led to his explanations of particle theory and the motion of molecules.",
        "similar_words": [],
        "title": "Albert Einstein",
        "url": "https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Albert_Einstein"
    },
    {
        "answer": "light",
        "question": "He also investigated the thermal properties of __________ and the quantum theory of radiation, the basis of the laser, which laid the foundation of the photon theory of light.",
        "similar_words": [
            "infrared",
            "ultraviolet"
        ],
        "title": "Albert Einstein",
        "url": "https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Albert_Einstein"
    },
    {
        "answer": "general theory",
        "question": "In 1917, he applied the __________ __________ of relativity to model the structure of the universe.In 1933, while Einstein was visiting the United States, Adolf Hitler came to power.",
        "similar_words": [],
        "title": "Albert Einstein",
        "url": "https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Albert_Einstein"
    },
    {
        "answer": "jewish background",
        "question": "Because of his __________ __________, Einstein did not return to Germany.",
        "similar_words": [],
        "title": "Albert Einstein",
        "url": "https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Albert_Einstein"
    },
    {
        "answer": "american citizen",
        "question": "He settled in the United States and became an __________ __________ in 1940.",
        "similar_words": [],
        "title": "Albert Einstein",
        "url": "https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Albert_Einstein"
    },
    {
        "answer": "d. roosevelt",
        "question": "On the eve of World War II, he endorsed a letter to President Franklin __________ __________ alerting him to the potential German nuclear weapons program and recommending that the US begin similar research.",
        "similar_words": [],
        "title": "Albert Einstein",
        "url": "https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Albert_Einstein"
    },
    {
        "answer": "idea",
        "question": "Einstein supported the Allies, but generally denounced the __________ of nuclear weapons.",
        "similar_words": [
            "acculturation",
            "belief",
            "education",
            "experience",
            "food",
            "goal",
            "heresy",
            "ignorance"
        ],
        "title": "Albert Einstein",
        "url": "https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Albert_Einstein"
    },
    {
        "answer": "death",
        "question": "Einstein was affiliated with the Institute for Advanced Study in Princeton, New Jersey, until his __________ in 1955.",
        "similar_words": [
            "acceleration",
            "avulsion",
            "birth",
            "break",
            "conversion",
            "damage",
            "deceleration",
            "decrease"
        ],
        "title": "Albert Einstein",
        "url": "https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Albert_Einstein"
    },
    {
        "answer": "originality",
        "question": "His intellectual achievements and __________ have made the word \"Einstein\" synonymous with \"genius\".",
        "similar_words": [
            "aptitude",
            "bilingualism",
            "capacity",
            "creativity",
            "faculty",
            "hand",
            "intelligence",
            "know-how"
        ],
        "title": "Albert Einstein",
        "url": "https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Albert_Einstein"
    },
    {
        "answer": "understanding",
        "question": "Eugene Wigner compared him to his contemporaries, writing that \"Einstein's __________ was deeper even than Jancsi von Neumann's.",
        "similar_words": [
            "awareness",
            "cognizance",
            "incognizance",
            "know",
            "prevision"
        ],
        "title": "Albert Einstein",
        "url": "https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Albert_Einstein"
    },
    {
        "answer": "mind",
        "question": "His __________ was both more penetrating and more original than von Neumann's.\"",
        "similar_words": [
            "ability",
            "attitude",
            "cognitive factor",
            "content",
            "episteme",
            "equivalent",
            "history",
            "inability"
        ],
        "title": "Albert Einstein",
        "url": "https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Albert_Einstein"
    },
    {
        "answer": "biological neuron",
        "question": "The connections of the __________ __________ are modeled as weights.",
        "similar_words": [],
        "title": "Neural network",
        "url": "https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Neural_network"
    },
    {
        "answer": "weight reflects",
        "question": "A positive __________ __________ an excitatory connection, while negative values mean inhibitory connections.",
        "similar_words": [],
        "title": "Neural network",
        "url": "https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Neural_network"
    },
    {
        "answer": "weight",
        "question": "All inputs are modified by a __________ and summed.",
        "similar_words": [
            "absorptivity",
            "deflection",
            "dissolubility",
            "drippiness",
            "elasticity",
            "fugacity",
            "heat content",
            "imperceptibility"
        ],
        "title": "Neural network",
        "url": "https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Neural_network"
    },
    {
        "answer": "activity",
        "question": "This __________ is referred to as a linear combination.",
        "similar_words": [
            "acquiring",
            "action",
            "assumption",
            "causing",
            "communication",
            "delivery",
            "departure",
            "derivation"
        ],
        "title": "Neural network",
        "url": "https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Neural_network"
    },
    {
        "answer": "example",
        "question": "For __________, an acceptable range of output is usually between 0 and 1, or it could be \u22121 and 1.",
        "similar_words": [
            "acquaintance",
            "background",
            "circumstance",
            "datum",
            "descriptor",
            "evidence",
            "fact",
            "predictor"
        ],
        "title": "Neural network",
        "url": "https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Neural_network"
    },
    {
        "answer": "modeling",
        "question": "These artificial networks may be used for predictive __________, adaptive control and applications where they can be trained via a dataset.",
        "similar_words": [
            "bronze",
            "bust",
            "carving",
            "marble",
            "mobile",
            "mold",
            "relief",
            "stabile"
        ],
        "title": "Neural network",
        "url": "https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Neural_network"
    },
    {
        "answer": "experience",
        "question": "Self-learning resulting from __________ can occur within networks, which can derive conclusions from a complex and seemingly unrelated set of information.",
        "similar_words": [
            "enlightenment",
            "eruditeness",
            "foundation",
            "physical education"
        ],
        "title": "Neural network",
        "url": "https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Neural_network"
    }
]